

Typescript, Javascript, ReasonML, Python, Swift, Java, Kotlin, Objective-C, C, C++, Ocaml primary.taras.vozniuk@gmail.com

🗣 Taiwan 🚆 github.com/ambientlight 😊 tarasvozniuk.com 📓 stackoverflow.com/users/2380455 🔃 in linkedin.com/in/tarasvozniuk/

### **SUMMARY**

Lead developer at GeoThings with broad expertise including mobile development, full-stack, cloud architecture, devops as well as deep learning. Most of my time now is occupied by full stack development, also by building and maintaining distributed systems hosted on AWS as well as on-premise(with kubernetes) which I really enjoyed thus far. My free time is largely spend tinkering with experimental stacks, most recently with CRDTs and distributed systems using them. My ideas and open source contribution gravitated towards better developer tooling.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Lead Developer, Software Architect | GeoThings | Taiwan | Aug 2017 - Present

- Achieved real-time query capabilities for OSM map data by building and maintaining custom worldwide map tile server on top of tilezen stack that encodes osm tags inside data tiles
- Improved performance, user experience and code quality by rewriting our old frontend angularjs codebase to angular4, as well as rebuilding set of leaflet GIS functionality on top of mapbox-gl
- Designed and built a scalable cloud-native infrastructure for our service on AWS utilizing lambdas & ECS behind ALB, aurora postgres, redis, S3 behind CloudFront CDN as we migrated our legacy infra from Azure.
- Made large-scale data collection possible by designing and building machine learning pipeline capable of extracting roadside objects with its locations from windshield cam videos by using YoloV3 for object detection and deep-sort for tracking.
- Helped achieving 99.9% uptime by providing almost 24x7 response rate (vocations included) for critical fixes and infrastructure issues
- Responsible for stack decisions for all our service and project and all infrastructure operations.
- Helped our team to embrace and adopt new stacks, functional and reactive paradigms, provided guidances to our interns, by building sample projects, hosting coding walkthroughs and 1on1 sessions

iOS Developer | GeoThings | Taiwan | Sept 2015 - Aug 2017

- Developed map-centric application on top of WhirlyGlobe-Maply and later MapboxGL
- Enabled survey collection in remote areas by building an offline-oriented location-based survey collection app in swift
- Helped to collect valuable typhoon dujuan data by writing few server-side swift components and crawlers in short time
- Improved code quality and application data flow by introducing redux and its single-store concepts into our app with ReSwift, also by subsequently porting ReSwift to android as ReKotlin.

iOS Developer | Sixnology | Taiwan | Apr 2013 - Aug 2014

Built DLNA-complient audio streaming player for iOS supporting media from local library, UPNP Media Servers, and Spotify.

# **RECOGNITIONS**

Winners - NCTU Seed Fund Competition: NCTU Startup Lab | Nov 2018

Inside the winning batch of NCTU entrepreneurial competition  $% \left( 1\right) =\left( 1\right) \left( 1\right)$ 

Best Potential Team Award - Beyond Future Mobility: MIT Media Lab X NCTU | Sept 2015

- Gathered a team of talented folks to build a personal flying assistant helium drone
- Won best potential team award among 31 teams participating in the workshop by demonstrating our prototype and the validity of our idea

#### **EDUCATION**

National Chiao Tung University | earned Jun 2015

Double Degree: B.S. Computer Science, B.S. Finance & Information Management

## **STACKS**

react, angular, react-native, electron, django, aws amplify, serverless, aws lambda, cloudformation, docker, aws ecs, kubernetes, postgresql, dynamodb, sqlite, neo4j, redis, realm, redux, rxjs, graphql, logux, pixijs, jest, selenium, webpack, fastlane, bitrise, githubactions, keras tensorflow, opencv

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

ReKotlin, AWS Amplify, tilequeue, reductive-dev-tools, reductive-observable, amplify-cli-action, bs-rx, GithubIssuesExtension